Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Sociology, honors theses SC4-4571
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Sociology, honors theses
1986-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Sociology
SC4-4571
1.25 Linear Feet (22 volumes in 4 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Sociology.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Sociology.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Department of Sociology in 2008 and 2010. Additional theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Student papers.; Sociology; Stanford University. Department of Sociology
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2008-296
  - Celio, Carolyn, Mixed-incomes, mixed blessings; the destruction and rebirth of the Summit Place Public Housing Development., May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Cheng, Diane, The importance of diversity in K-12 schooling: parent opinions on the school assignment process, resegregation trends, and race-conscious student assignment in the San Francisco Unified School District., May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Groden, Darcey, An early modern social movement: applying the poliltical process model to Civil War England., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Lor, Yang, Immigrant political incorporation: a case study of Hmong political involvement in Fresno, California and St. Paul, Minnesota., 2008 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2010-123
  - Anderson, Nadina, A Comparative analysis: teachers' perceptions of autonomy in differing school structures., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Harwin, Alexandra, Familial support in mathematics: a study on the association between early parental support and preparation for college level mathematics for Latino and European American students., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Hernandez, Yessica, Painting the streets: evolution of muralism in San Francisco, California., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Smith, Emilyn, The sustainable, organic, and local (SOL) food movement in the Bay Area., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Zarrow, Allison Lee, Do downtowns matter: a case study of dispersing "civic fauna" in Tulsa, Oklahoma., 2010 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Gera, Jennifer Lyn, Work requirements and welfare reform: assumptions, implementation, and the effect on persistent poverty., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Hwang, Jackelyn, Perceptions and borders of the changing neighborhood: a case study in Philadelphia., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Kang, David L., The great engine war: a garbage can perspective., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Rice, David A. and Tracy A. Thompson, What makes a happy "techie"? A needs-satisfaction model approach to worker satisfaction., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Vargas, Theresa, Nuestras palabras (our words): an ethnographic view of female Mexican-American youth in San Antonio, Texas., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Vernon, Fox, Student and culture: the influences of Stanford on students' intellectual attitudes., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Bajaj, Monisha, Paradi Pèdi': Haitian migrant women in the Dominican Republic., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Erlin, H. Christopher W. and Bonnie J. McLean, Normalizing illegitimate acts., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Ellis, Sara, The Grameen bank: how microcredit empowers women in rural Bangladesh., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Turley, Ruth N. López, Ethnic collective action and ethnic organizations on college campuses: a case study of Stanford University., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Mandebaum, Bari, A new approach to domestic violence: a socio-psychological analysis of domestic violence using Emerson's Power Dependence Theory., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Gillaspy, Betsy A., A study of the differences and similarities in the sexual standards and behaviors of Southern and non-Southern women at Stanford University., 1987 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Diaz, Teri, "Gender and juvenile delinquency; an investigation of how family risk factors vary for delinquent boys and girls and relate to their propensities to commit violent crimes", 2011 May 16 (Box 1)